using the presentation that I created in
session 1 I now need to add some further
information into the slide show so I
have the for slate and only a continue
at the moment with some text now on
slate - I'm going to add each shot well
I'm also going to show how this could be
added as a table so you do have options
there's various things that you can
insert but I'm going to add a chart to
this but I will also demonstrate how you
can assure that information in the table
if you prefer so the first thing I need
to do is looking at the layout of the
slate
it isn't really suitable for adding a
chart or a table unless I place it
underneath but the first thing I need to
do and the easiest way to add a chart or
a table alongside text is to change the
layout of the slate so if I go to the
slides icon and then select the layout
this will tell me that currently this is
a title and content slate now I want to
change that to a title and 2 content so
if I do that it automatically changes it
on the slate and PowerPoint kindly pops
up some design ideas I don't wish to use
them so I'll just click off that so
quite simply I am now able to insert a
range of objects into the slate and if
you click on each of the icons it will
tell you what each one is now the first
instance I'm just going to insert a
table just to demonstrate so I can
select insert table and it asks me for
the number of columns and rows now I
have the information on a spreadsheet
yes I know it needs two columns and
seven rows so far just select two
columns seven rows
select ok now that is creating the table
so I still need to populate our table so
what I would need to do is I need a go
to my spreadsheet use ctrl C to select
the data select the presentation click
in the first box and then ctrl + V which
would then Pierce the information in and
then I could make adjustments as you can
see the text is quite smaller than 1 so
I go to home and change that to share
the text I wish
for our wheel making size 60 and then I
can also resize the table to suit if I
just click on the table like and then
change the table style and art various
of our foreman and options so that is
how you would insert a table into the
presentation I'm just going to undo that
because what I want to add is actually a
chart so what I want to do is again
there are two ways you can do that if
you click on the insert shot and then
select the type of chart that you wish
and I will insert a line shot and click
on line and it will give me a default
chart and I can see which you want to
Lake and I'll just go far stock Lane
Lane so there's various charts that you
can select I'm just going to go for a
lane shot select look here now again it
is insert of the chart but I still have
to add the information so I would need
to take the information that is here and
place it into this one here or
alternatively I can just undo what I did
on there so I'll click the undo and all
I would need to do then is I have a
chart that I've actually created in
Excel using that theater so I just
select that and copy that go to the
PowerPoint select there kiss that that
is now added the chart and again I can
then edit the chart to change the text
within the chart aerial it's slightly
bigger and that will let me make any
amendments I can also add various other
features the access titles I can format
the charts with a stale in the color no
changes to that and one of the things
that as a benefit is that you can
actually make a change to the data in
the spreadsheet and then if you go back
to your presentation will automatically
the dearest what is linked the chart to
the actual presentation